# Arnulfo Israel Ramos Magaña

## Fullstack Application Developer

Guadalajara, Jalisco +52 341-136-2414 a.israel.ramos.m@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/israel-ramos israelramosm.github.io

## **Summary**

I am a Telematics Engineer with over eight years of experience developing web applications using Javascript/Typescript, Java, and C#. I mainly developed applications using nodejs with frameworks like <a href="expressis">expressis</a> and nestjs as the backend and react/redux and svelte as the front end. I also worked with IBM Cloud technologies such as Event Streams, which is based on Kafka, and NoSQL databases. My strengths are problem-solving, technology, communication, fast learner, and personal development.

### **Experience**

#### Full Stack Developer

2020-10 - 2024-05

IRI/

Responsible for developing and migrating applications to new technologies using frontend frameworks such as react/redux and svelte, backend frameworks such as expressjs and nestjs, and working with IBM cloud technologies and resources.

- Optimized the usability of the legacy application system to help employees with informational and behavioral issues within the organization by developing a new frontend application using react/redux and expressjs.
- Attended technical tickets that users raised on the application by talking to the user about the problems
  maintaining and supporting the frontend application developed in react/redux and expressjs for any errors.
- Facilitated the development experience for my teammates by configuring, developing, and monitoring IBM Cloud resources used within the applications.
- Lead event-driven microservices development using IBM Cloud technologies such as Event Streams built on Kafka to create cases within applications.
- Built and developed the user experience of new internal applications that create specific cases for the IBM business model using technologies and frameworks such as Svelte for the front end and nestjs for the back end.

Java Developer 2019-02 - 2020-10

Tata Consultancy Services

Responsible for developing and maintaining the backend and the frontend applications using Java as the main language.

- Gave maintenance and support for the credit cards and loans area by updating the code according to client requirements.
- Collaborated with the Learning and Development team within the office, creating and developing applications using technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, and JQuery.
- Created and organized meetings with other teammates to teach them new technologies used in the office and the company's projects.
- I was part of the office's onboarding team, which followed up, resolved questions, and guided new developers.

#### **Software Engineer** 2016-09 - 2018-12

Unosquare

Responsible for developing various applications and projects using different technologies and frameworks such as Angular, React, C# .NET, and .NET Core and devices such as Raspberry Pi for internal and external use

- Developed the company's main page using technologies such as HTML5, Javascript, CSS3, and C#.
   NET, creating the views, home, and information page.
- Maintenance and development of the company's private and open-source projects using technologies such as Angular, React, Javascript, C# .NET, Raspberry Pi, and .NET Core technologies.
- Microsoft certification exams 480, 486, and 487.

#### **Education**

## Telematics Engineer

Guadalajara University

#### 2013 - 2016

# Language and Software

#### English - C1

Experienced Basic/Intermediate

Javascript Java
Typescript AngularJs
Nodejs JQuery
Nestjs C#

React/Redux ASP.NET
Expressjs .NET Core
IBM Cloud Bootstrap
REST Webpack

Git
HTML5
CSS3
Sass

## Certifications

| IBM Certified Advocate - Cloud v2                       | 2019-04 |
|---|---------|
| Exam 487: Developing Microsoft Azure and Web Services   | 2017-03 |
| MCSD: App Builder — Certified 2017                      | 2017-03 |
| Exam 486: Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications       | 2017-01 |
| MCSA: Web Applications - Certified 2017                 | 2017-01 |
| Exam 480: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 | 2016-11 |